A Guide to the Rockefeller Foundation records, Audiovisual materials FA752
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Rockefeller Foundation Audio, 1954 - 1980; 3; 130 Reels Audio
  - J. George Harrar Interview with Greer Williams, 1963 April 11; Sound, 55 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15253)
    A transcript of this interview is found in the Rockefeller Foundation Program and Policy records, SG 3.1 (FA112), Series 908, Box 7A, folder 86.5 (History - Greer Williams' Notes - J. G. Harrar).
  - John H. Knowles's Wednesday Morning Officers Meeting, with Daniel Patrick Moynihan, 1973 January 31; Sound, 2 hours 33 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15254)
    Moynihan was the invited speaker.
    The meeting discussion is found at 00:24:00 - 01:23:10. Moynihan's remarks begin around 01:23:10 and run to the end of the recording (02:32:40). The remarks and a question and answer period then continue from the beginning of recording to 00:23:59.
  - Kenneth W. Thompson and Scarsdale High School Faculty on the Teaching of Social Studies, 1973 February 2; Sound, 2 hours 17 minutes (full tape runs 3 hours 28 minutes).; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15255)
    Presentation to the Rockefeller Foundation. Panel composed of Scarsdale High School Social Studies teachers Judith Oxner, Werner Feig, Eric Rothschild, and Eugene Pisani. Program organized by Kenneth W. Thompson. Recording runs from 00:00 - 02:16:19.
    From 02:40:23 - 03:27:35 there is also an unrelated and unidentified discussion by John H. Knowles concerning the Rockefeller Foundation's general program review and direction.
  - Michel Oksenberg on Contemporary China, 1973 April 11; Sound, 62 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15256)
    First presentation in a series of seminars for RF staff. The recording cuts off the question and answer period at the end.
  - Conquest of Hunger Meeting, 1973 May 3; Sound, 6 hours and 2 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15257)
    Meeting at the Rockefeller Foundation of officers and staff in the agricultural and social sciences and invited guests. Discussion focused on the socioeconomic aspects of world food production and the role of social scientists in the Conquest of Hunger effort.
  - Continuing Education in the Humanities - Michael Novak Conference, 1973 May 9; Sound, 2 hours 21 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15258)
    Participants mainly included Columbia University faculty in various disciplines and Rockefeller Foundation officers.
  - American Music Recording Project, Discussion Meeting, [1973] May 10; Sound, 2 hours 37 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15259)
    Second meeting with Howard Klein and invited guests to discuss scope and criteria for a proposed project to create a Recorded Anthology of American Music.
  - Robert Goheen on Foundations, 1973 April 25; Sound, 65 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15260)
    Seminar for Rockefeller Foundation staff.
  - James MacGregor Burns, 1973 May 18; Sound, 22 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15261)
    Recording begins in the middle of a discussion period on general topic of education and American civic understanding.
  - Vincent P. Dole, Wednesday Morning Seminar on Drug Abuse, 1973 May 16; Sound, 86 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15262)
    Discussion of narcotics addiction, medical studies, effectiveness of methadone programs, and misguidedness of repressive responses to the problem.
  - Pluralistic Sensibilities in the Humanities - Michael Novak Conference, 1973 May 11; Sound, 6 hours 8 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15263)
  - J. George Harrar Speaks to Rockefeller Foundation Officers about His China Tour, 1973 July 3; Sound, 87 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15264)
    Includes introduction by John H. Knowles. Harrar spoke at meeting of Rockefeller Foundation officers.
  - Fr. Andrew Greeley and Michael Novak Speak to John H. Knowles and Rockefeller Foundation Officers, 1972 November 22; Sound, 108 minutes. There is an audible hum in the background of the recording.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15265)
    Address to the Wednesday morning officers' meeting.
  - Mayor of Boston Kevin White on topic of American Cities and Urban Problems, 1973 July 18; Sound, 64 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15266)
    Wednesday morning seminar? (Address to the Rockefeller Foundation staff.)
  - Michael Novak - Seminar on the Humanities, 1973 July 25; Sound, 3 hours 55 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15267)
    John H. Knowles began the meeting by discussing the history of Rockefeller Foundation support for the Humanities and the Foundation's current review of its Humanities program, of which this seminar was one component. This seminar in particular gathered philosophers and various Rockefeller Foundation officers.
  - Hudson Basin Project Meeting, 1973 September 11; Sound, 67 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15268)
    Project organization and planning meeting with Ralph W. Richardson and committee. Morning session not recorded - afternoon session recorded on Side 1.
  - Aquaculture Conference - John A. Pino, 1973 October 2; Sound, 2 hours 56 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15269)
    Speakers: David Wallace, Burr Steinbach, Alexander Spoehr, Barry Fisher, and Harold Goodwin. The last presentation (by Harold Goodwin) appears first on the recording. The introductory presentation by John A. Pino and the other speakers then follow (beginning at around 38 minutes).
  - Otto Feinstein, Neighborhoods and Cities, 1973 September 26; Sound, 93 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15270)
    Wednesday Morning Seminar with Otto Feinstein, Director of Urban Studies at Wayne State University. Feinstein spoke on topic of Social and Political Problems of Ethnicity in Urban Areas.
  - James Grant of Overseas Development Council, 1973 October 17; Sound, 87 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15271)
    Wednesday Morning Seminar, on topic of Developing Countries and U.S. Foreign Policy.
  - Conference on Plant Resistance to Insect Attack, 1973 October 30; Sound, 3 hours 5 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15272)
    Conference at Rockefeller Foundation offices, discussing results of foundation-sponsored research and next directions. Recording covers morning session only.
  - Joseph Papp on Values in Contemporary Life, 1973 October 31; Sound, 81 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15273)
    Wednesday seminar? Papp spoke about theater and contemporary understandings, and, in particular, about reactions to David Rabe's "In the Boom Boom Room," which was just then opening under Papp's direction at Lincoln Center Theater.
  - Journalism and the Humanities Conference, 1973 November 12; Sound, 3 hours 25 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 1, Reel AV 15274)
    Foundation-initiated conference, organized by Michael Novak. The concluding session appears first on the recording (and ends at around 62 minutes). The recording of the initial, morning sessions starts at around 70 minutes.
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Peter Berger on Development Policy and the Calculus of Meaning, 1969 December; Sound, 63 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15304)
    John H. Knowles's Wednesday Morning Seminar. Berger was professor of Sociology at Rutgers University.
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Earl O. Heady on Rural Community Development in the United States, 1974 January 9; Sound, 2 hours 16 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15305)
  - Conference on Weather and Climate Change, Food Production, and Inter-State Conflict, 1974 January 24; Sound, 5 hours 33 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15306)
    Day one of a two-day meeting at the Rockefeller Foundation. Organized by Elmore Jackson.
  - Conference on Weather and Climate Change, Food Production, and Inter-State Conflict, 1974 January 25; Sound, 110 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15307)
    Day two of a two-day meeting at the Rockefeller Foundation. Organized by Elmore Jackson.
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Program Related Investments and the Ford Foundation's Use of This Device, 1974 February 15; Sound, 75 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15308)
    Arthur Trottenburg, Eamon Kelly, Paul Feinberg, and James Jordan spoke on behalf of the Ford Foundation. John H. Knowles presided.
  - Education for Development Field Staff Meeting (Day 1, Morning Session), 1973 November 19; Sound, 4 hours 22 minutes (the recorded content runs approximately 2 hours 51 minutes; the last 90 minutes are blank).; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15309)
    Meeting chaired by Ralph K. Davidson. John H. Knowles presented a detailed account of the Rockefeller Foundation's program review at the start of the meeting.
  - Education for Development Field Staff Meeting (Day 1, Afternoon Session), 1973 November 19; Sound, 2 hours 25 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15310)
    Ralph K. Davidson chaired the meeting.
  - Education for Development Field Staff Meeting (Day 2), 1973 November 20; Sound, 6 hours 20 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15311)
    Ralph K. Davidson chaired the meeting. Day 2, morning and afternoon sessions. The meeting adjourns on the recording at around 4 hours 12 minutes. The recording is silent for about 45 minutes; it then resumes at around 5 hours 1 minute with a discussion of regulations concerning scholars and foreign students, followed by presentations on Brazil and Colombia (from 5 hours 32 minutes to the end). The recording cuts off at the end, and it is not known where these presentations fell in the day's agenda.
  - Michael P. Todaro - Conference and Bellagio Project on Higher Education for Development, 1974 February 11; Sound, 3 hours 34 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15313)
  - Michael P. Todaro - Conference and Bellagio Project on Higher Education for Development, 1974 February 12; Sound, 5 hours 38 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15323)
  - Gary H. Toenniessen - Conference on International River Basins, 1974 February 22; Sound, 4 hours 40 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15312)
    Conference at the Rockefeller Foundation.
  - Lester Brown - Overseas Development Council, 1974 February 27; Sound, 81 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15318)
    Wednesday staff seminar on Implications of Global Interdependence: The World Food and Energy Situation.
  - Robert Roosa - The International Monetary System: Past, Present, and Future, 1974 March 6; Sound, 86 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15314)
    Wednesday morning staff seminar.
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Gilbert White on Global Changes: Important New Areas for International Scientific Research, 1974 March 27; Sound, recording length 92 minutes (tape runs 2 hours 8 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15315)
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Dr. Marshall Shulman on Prospects for Strategic and Conventional Arms Control, 1974 April 24; Sound, 116 minutes recording length (tape runs 3 hours 12 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15317)
  - Bellagio Conference on Pesticides, 1974 April; Sound, 5 hours 55 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15339)
    The Future for Insecticides: Needs and Prospects. Rockefeller Foundation conference at Bellagio, April 22-27, 1974.
  - Bellagio Conference on Pesticides, 1974 April; Sound, 6 hours 13 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15340)
  - Partisan Review Conference on the State of the Humanities, 1974 May 10; Sound, 5 hours 18 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15319)
    Conference cosponsored with the Rockefeller Foundation, held at the RF offices. For related materials see Rockefeller Foundation records, RG 3.2, Series 911, box 10, folder 54 (Program and Policy - Partisan Review, 1974). Note on original tape indicates "Transcribed Martin [C.?]." Conference papers by William Phillips, Steven Marcus, and Richard Poirier published in the Partisan Review, 41, no. 4 (Fall 1974).
  - Wednesday Morning Seminar - Joel Fleishman on the Role of Humanities in Public Policy Analysis, 1974 May 22; Sound, 50 minutes of recording (tape runs 3 hours 15 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15321)
    The recording begins in mid-discussion. The beginning of the presentation is missing.
  - Michael Novak Conference, 1974 May 29; Sound, 82 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15324)
    Members of the Center for Advanced Study in Religion and Science (CASIRAS), John Knowles, and others on the relating of science, humanities, and religion, and the contemporary need for a new moral framework.
  - Sheldon Segal, Vice President for Biomedical Sciences Division of the Population Council, 1974 June 5; Sound, 102 minutes recorded length (tape runs 3 hours 36 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15322)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting
  - Plant Symposium - Allan C. Barnes, 1974 June 10; Sound, 4 hours 14 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15326)
    Exploratory meeting of Rockefeller Foundation, Ford Foundation, and Population Council representatives with a group of experts concerning the possible magnitude of conducting a global search for contraceptives in the plant world.
    The recording begins with the afternoon session (concluding at 01:27:35); the initial morning session then follows from 01:28 to the end.
  - Michael Novak, "The Cure of Souls" (Seven Theologians), 1974 June 22; Sound, 5 hours 28 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15320)
    Discussion on theological education, religious studies, and cultural values, with a view to possible intersections with the RF humanities program.
  - John H. Knowles, Health Meeting - Commission on Critical Choices, 1974 June 26; Sound, 3 hours 38 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15325)
    Initial Health Panel meeting.
  - C. Fred Bergsten on Implications of Shortages and Inflation for the International System, 1974 July 31; Sound, 110 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15327)
    Wednesday Morning Seminar. Bergsten particularly addressed the development of contrived, not physical, shortages in international commodity markets.
  - Antonio Carillo Flores, Secretary General of the United Nations World Population Conference, on "All Things Considered", 1974 July 31; Sound, 9 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15331)
    Interview with Susan Stamberg.
  - Arts Program, American Music Recording Project Meeting, 1974 September 20; Sound, 3 hours 42 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15328)
  - Report from Bucharest - The United Nations World Population Conference, 1974 September 29; Sound, 59 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15332)
    National Public Radio program "Options," with Jeff Rosenberg.
  - Ambassador John R. Stevenson on United Nations Law of the Sea Conference in Venezuela, 1974 October 2; Sound, 81 minutes (recording runs 5 hours 26 minutes in all); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15329)
    Wednesday Morning Seminar. Stevenson attended the conference as Special Representative of the President.
    Stevenson's talk was recorded on the same tape as (and over) a prior, undated meeting to evaluate grants made to four universities to fund research and education in environmental studies. The recording of the environmental studies discussion starts at 01:21:32 and runs to the end, 05:25:57.
  - American Music Recording Project Meeting with Herman Krawitz; Arts Program Meeting concerning International Dance Programs, 1974 October 1; 1974 October 11; Sound, 3 hours 29 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15330)
    Recording project report and discussion with Herman Krawitz (00:01:45 - 01:54:00). RF-sponsored discussion meeting on UNESCO cultural programs, the International Theatre Institute (ITI), international dance programs, and general support for dance (01:54:00 - end). Participants include Barbara J. Good, Rosamund Gilder, Roger Englander, and others. The recording appears to cover the afternoon meeting only.
  - Second Rockefeller Foundation Forum on the Arts, 1974 November 18-19; Sound, 3 hours 52 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15333)
    How Can Foundations Help the Arts? Discussion with various foundation leaders on how to interest other national and local foundations in supporting the arts.
  - Margaret Mead on Women in Agriculture, 1974 December 18; Sound, 144 minutes (recording runs 168 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15348)
  - Colin Turnbull on the Ethics of Starvation, 1975 February 5; Sound, 2 hours 16 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15338)
  - Derek Bok and John H. Knowles Discuss Africa with Staff, 1975 March 13; Sound, 111 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15334)
  - Joel Colton and Elizabeth Janeway, 1975 March 26; Sound, 86 minutes (recording runs 2 hours and 25 minutes in total).; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15335)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting; discussion concerning adult learners and education.
    Recording resumes (at 01:27 to end), with an unidentified (but presumably earlier) discussion meeting at the Rockefeller Foundation on Equal Opportunity programs.
  - Dr. Virginia A. Church on Legal Education, 1975 April 23; Sound, 90 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15336)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting. Dr. Church was dean of the newly established School of Law at Lewis University, in Illinois.
  - James Hester on the United Nations University, 1975 June 4; Sound, 123 minutes. (The full recording runs 140 minutes.); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 2, Reel AV 15337)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting. Hester, immediate past president of New York University, had been appointed rector (i.e., president) of the newly formed United Nations University in November 1974.
    The discussion with Hester ends at 02:02:45. The tape then cuts in on a separate and unidentified discussion with Vernon Jordan (17 minutes, from 02:02:46 to the end).
  - Eleanor Holmes Norton, Chair of the New York City Commission on Human Rights, 1976 February 11; Sound, 127 minutes (including an 8-minute gap in the middle). The full recording runs 144 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15341)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting. There is an interruption (with music) in the recording from approximately 01:15:30 to 01:23:30.
  - Robert Coles, 1976 February 25; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15343)
  - Humanities Centers, 1976 March 18; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15342)
  - Dr. Josue Gonzalez: Bilingual and Bicultural Education, 1976 May 19; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15344)
  - George Bundy, 1976 July 14; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15346)
  - Wed Morning Meetings Chaired by Elmore Jackson, 1976 July 26; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15345)
  - Unidentified Committee Meeting, Evaluating Applications for Small Grants in Areas of Population and Health Education, 1976 July 21; Sound, 6 hours 13 minutes; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15347)
    Meeting to evaluate applications from both the U.S. and developing countries for small grants to study issues of population, health education, migration, infant mortality, etc.
  - JC Meeting Richard Sennett Conference, 1975 January 31; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15349)
  - JC - Dissent Meeting, 1975 May 1; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15350)
  - Dr. Raymond Moody, 1975 December 8; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15351)
  - Jacques Barzun, 1976 December 15; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15352)
  - Maurice Langham, 1977 January 19; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15353)
  - Rostow, 1977 January 12; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15354)
  - Stuart Mott - Foundations and Politics, 1977 February 2; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15355)
  - Women's History - Joan Gadol, 1977 March 9; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15356)
  - Herbert Gutman, 1977 January 5; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15357)
  - HK Meeting Underground TV Meeting, 1975 May 22; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15358)
  - Ann Coste - Discussing Programs of Rockefeller Family Fund, 1977 May 19; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15359)
  - Sir Leon Radzinowicz Subject: The growth of crime; the international experience, 1977 April 4; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15360)
  - Paul Friedman, 1977 June 29; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15361)
  - Max Lerner New York Post "Third Century America", 1977 April 26; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15362)
  - Allard Lowenstein, 1977 October 31; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15363)
  - Ben Hooks - NAACP, 1977 November 16; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15364)
  - Dr. David Shear and Michael Feldstein Meeting on USAID Programs in the Sahel, 1977 November 23; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15365)
  - Frances Fitzgerald, 1976 November 18; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15366)
  - Livingston Biddle Re: Government and Grants for Arts and Humanities, 1977 March 23; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15367)
  - Edward T Hall, 1977 December 14; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15368)
  - Willrich talk on Energy program, 1977 April 28; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 3, Reel AV 15369)
  - Villa Conference - Management of Interdependence, 1975 May 11; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15370)
  - Villa Conference - Management of Interdependence, 1975 May 12; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15371)
  - Villa Conference - Management of Interdependence, 1975 May 13; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15372)
  - Bellagio Conference, Humanities and Social Thought (Days 1 and 2), 1977 June 2-3; Sound, 6 hours 24 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15373)
  - Bellagio Conference, Humanities and Social Thought (Concluding Session), 1977 June; Sound, 28 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15374)
  - Bellagio Conference, Humanities and Social Thought, 1977 June; Sound, 6 hours 28 minutes.; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15375)
    Includes discussions on language, and on Lacan and psychoanalysis, among other subjects.
  - Duplicates June 6 Session, 1977 June 6; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15376)
  - Program and Policy Value Consensus Conference, 1978 March 28-29; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15377)
  - Bellagio Humanities Conference, 1974; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15378)
  - Bellagio Humanities Conference, 1974; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15379)
  - Bellagio Humanities Conference, 1974; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15380)
  - Bellagio Humanities Conference, 1974; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15381)
  - Conference on the Possibility of Cooperation between the NEH and the Private Humanities Foundations, 1980 July 17; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15382)
  - Conference on Relationship between Humanities and Public Policy, 1980 July 17; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15383)
  - Sheldon J. Segal on His Visit to China on behalf of the RF, 1979 February 21; Sound, 70 minutes (recording runs for 123 minutes); 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15384)
    Wednesday Morning Meeting. Segal was director of the RF's Population Sciences division.
  - Women, Society and Work Conference The Journal of Family History and Signs, 1978 September 21-22; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15385)
  - Women, Society and Work Conference The Journal of Family History and Signs, 1978 September 22; Sound,; 1/4 inch audio tape (Box 4, Reel AV 15386)